=Romance of a Twin Flower=
= رومانسية زهرة مزدوجة =
=Episode 9=
= الحلقة 9 =
In this case,
في هذه الحالة
I bet His Majesty sends Ning Yuxuan to Haifang
أراهن على جلالة الإمبراطور أرسل نينغ يويشوان إلى هيفانغ
because he's after something else.
لأنه يسعى إلى شيء آخر
Muxu,
موكس
when will he be back?
متى سيعود؟
Tomorrow noontime.
غدًا وفي وقت لاحق
He'll be back tomorrow?
سيعود غدًا؟
Great. Perfect.
رائع، ممتاز
He's been through hell
لقد مر بالجحيم
in jail these days.
في السجن هذه الأيام
We'll prepare a nice
سنقوم بتحضير حفل لطيف
homecoming party for him tomorrow.
حفل استقبال له غدا
Finally, he's coming home.
أخيرا، إنه يعود إلى المنزل
(Ning's Mansion)
(حفل نينغ)
Second Lady,
السيدة الثانية
His Lordship should be home by now, shouldn't he?
يجب أن يكون سيادته بالمنزل الآن ألا ينبغي أن يكون؟
Right. It's about time.
صحيح لقد حان الوقت
Yeah.
نعم
Let's wait a bit longer.
دعنا ننتظر لفترة أطول
There he is.
ها هو ذا
You are all here.
أنت جميعا هنا
Your Lordship, it mustn't be easy for you.
سيادتك يجب ألا يكون الأمر سهلا بالنسبة لك
You've even lost weight.
فقدت بعض الوزن حتى
You're home at last.
أنت إلى المنزل أخيرا
- Your Lordship.
- سيادتك
You wish to see Her Ladyship, don't you?
أتمنى أن ترى سيدتها أليس كذلك؟
Make way.
ابتعد
Be careful.
توخي الحذر
Make way. Make way.
افسح الطريق
Watch out. Watch out.
احترسوا، احرسوا
- Watch out. - Be careful.
- احترس - كوني حذرة
You're home, Ning Yuxuan.
أنت في المنزل، نينغ يوتشوان
Nie Sangyu,
نيه سانغيو
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
This is the homecoming ceremony
هذا هو حفل استقبال
that I prepared for you.
الذي أعددته لك
You want me to step across the brazier?
تريدني أن أتدخل عبر البرازيل؟
I know
أعلم
that it hasn't been easy for you
أن الأمر لم يكن سهلا عليك
in jail in the past days,
في السجن في الأيام الماضية
so today,
لذلك اليوم
you will step across the brazier
سوف تتخطى البرازيل
full of burning willow branches
مليء بالفروع البرية المحترقة
to expunge your bad luck.
للقضاء على حظك السيئ
Take it away.
خذه بعيدا
What?
ماذا؟
I ask you to take it away.
أطلب منك أن تخلعيه
Listen,
اسمعا
don't feel embarrassed.
لا تشعري بالحرج
It will burn out soon,
سيطلق النار قريبًا
and it won't work.
ولن ينجح
Come on.
هيا
Thank you very much.
شكرًا جزيلًا لك
Hey.
أنت
You are supposed to step across it.
من المفترض أن تتخطى ذلك
Weird.
غريب
Close the door.
أغلقي الباب
She's unbelievable.
هذا لا يُصدّق
I heard that she did some good things
سمعت أنها فعلت أشياء جيدة
when I was in jail.
عندما كنت في السجن
But as soon as I'm home,
لكن حالما أعود إلى المنزل
she starts to do crazy stuff again.
تبدأ بفعل الأشياء المجنونة مجددًا
I…
أنا...
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
you may have got her wrong.
ربما أسأت فهمها
Look at the basin full of water
انظر إلى الحوض المليء بالمياه
with grapefruit leaves in it,
مع أوراق ثمار العنب فيها
I bet she went to the market
أراهن أنها ذهبت إلى السوق
to buy the freshest leaves
لشراء أحدث الأوراق
specifically for you.
تحديدا لك
In my opinion,
في رأيي
she's serious about dispelling
إنها جادة في تبديد
bad luck from you.
حظًا سيئًا منك
What grapefruit leaves?
أي أوراق العنب؟
Grapefruit leaves and brazier-crossing?
أوراق العنب وعبور الشفاه؟
I don't believe they will do anything.
لا أعتقد أنهم سيفعلون أي شيء
Superstitious stuff.
أشياء خرافية
Out you go.
ابتعد عنك
I need to rest.
أحتاج إلى الراحة
Yes.
نعم
I wonder
أتساءل
what else
ماذا أيضًا
Nie Sangyu
نيه سانغيو
put in the basin.
وضعت في الحوض
Grapefruit leaves.
أوراق العنب الفاكهة
Stepping across a brazier.
عبر البرازيل أكثر
Unbelievable.
هذا لا يُصدّق
It is strange enough
من الغريب بما فيه الكفاية
that the Tea Gang appeared in Haifang.
أن تيا غانغ ظهر في هيفانغ
And now that Ning Yuxuan
والآن بعد أن نينغ يويشوان
was demoted and sent to Haifang,
تم خفض رتبته وإرساله إلى هيفانغ
I have every reason to go there.
لدي كل سبب للذهاب إلى هناك
I see you have made up your mind,
أراك أنك قد فهمت
so I won't waste my breath anymore.
لذلك لن أضيع أنفاسي بعد الآن
Be careful during your journey.
كن حذرًا خلال رحلتك
Uncle,
العم
take care.
اعتني بنفسك
Amitabha.
أميتابها
The priggish scholars were supposed to be dealt with,
فقهاء القانون كان من المفترض أن يتم التعامل معهم
but it got delayed
لكن الأمر تأخر
because I was put in jail.
لأنني وضعت في السجن
It has to be taken care of before we go.
يجب أن نهتم به قبل أن نذهب
Yes.
نعم
You were freed
تم إطلاق سراحك
because Her Ladyship
لأن سيدتها
built up your reputation
بنيت سمعتك
through the priggish scholars.
من خلال علماء الغاضبين
Someone's poison
سم شخص ما
can be others' medicine.
يمكن أن يكون دواء للآخرين
Every person is to be handled with different strategy.
يجب معالجة كل شخص باستراتيجية مختلفة
No sweeping generalization.
لا تعميم واسع
Understood.
مفهوم
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
we are to go to Haifang
علينا أن نذهب إلى هيفانغ
in a rush.
في عجلة من أمرك
Will you go on your own
هل ستذهب بمفردك
or…
أو...
Nie Sangyu offended Ling Jianxing,
أسأت نيس سانغيو لينغ جيانشينغ
thus the incident of priggish scholars arose.
ومن ثم ثار حادث علماء منافسين
It concerns me
يثير قلقي
that she's kept in the capital.
أنها يتم الاحتفاظ بها في العاصمة
I'll think about it.
سأفكر في ذلك
Ning Yuxuan.
نينغ يوتشوان
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Why did you refuse to step across the brazier?
لماذا رفضت أن تتخطى البرازيل؟
You just got out of jail.
خرجت من السجن للتو
You are to step across a brazier
عليك أن تتخطى البرازيل
with burning willow branches in it
بحرق الفروع البريئة فيه
for your bad luck
من أجل حظك السيئ
to be dispelled.
ليتم التخلص منه
I have never
لم يسبق لي
been a superstitious person.
لم أكن شخصا خرافيا
Ugh, what a waste of my breath.
أولًا، يا له من إهدار لأنفاسي
Wait.
انتظر
What?
ماذا؟
You will follow me
سوف تتبعني
to Haifang.
إلى هيفانغ
You want me to go with you?
هل تريد مني أن أذهب معك؟
No.
لا
I'm planning to open up a shop in the capital.
أخطط لفتح متجر في العاصمة
I…
أنا...
Your Lordship.
سيادتك
Miss Wen, what's up?
الآنسة وين، ما الأمر؟
I wanted to see you.
أردت رؤيتك
Good to see you, Your Ladyship.
هنيئًا أن أراك يا سيدتك
Miss Wen.
الآنسة وين
You must have
يجب أن تكون
gone through a lot, Your Lordship.
مررت بالكثير، يا سيادتك
Your sacrifice for the nation
التضحية بك من أجل الأمة
shall be noted by His Majesty.
يجب أن لاحظ جلالة الإمبراطور
I'm sure
أنا متأكد
you'll be reinstated someday.
سيتم إعادتها يوما ما
What is the matter?
ما هو الأمر؟
I have heard that it is hot and humid in Haifang.
لقد سمعت أنه حار ورطب في هيفانغ
I'm worried
أنا قلق
that you won't get used to the weather.
أنك لن تعتاد الطقس
So I suggest
لذلك أقترح
you take me with you.
تأخذين معي
I can at least cook something
يمكنني على الأقل طهي شيئًا ما
that you like to eat.
الذي تحبين تناوله
Yeah,
نعم
you can take Miss Wen away with you.
يمكنك أخذ الآنسة وين معك
I'll pass…
لا، شكرا لك
Thanks but no.
شكرًا ولكن لا
I don't care for food.
لا يهمني الطعام
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
I have heard that many people do business in Haifang,
لقد سمعت أن العديد من الناس يمارسون الأعمال في هيفانغ
and there are so many novelties.
وهناك الكثير من الروايات
I'd like to go shopping.
أود أن أذهب للتسوق
And I've also been told
و
that they sell all kinds of snacks
أنهم يبيعون جميع أنواع الوجبات الخفيفة
that are all delicious,
التي كلها لذيذة
and they are not available in the capital.
ولا تتوافر في العاصمة
How I wish to try some!
كيف أرغب في تجربة بعض!
Really?
حقا؟
Many people do business in Haifang
العديد من الناس يقومون بأعمال تجارية في هيفانغ
and
و
they sell all sorts of novelties?
كل أنواع الروايات؟
Yeah.
نعم
Miss Wen,
الآنسة وين
how about
ماذا عن
I go with you?
أنا أذهب معك؟
So that you won't be bored
حتى لا تشعري بالملل
on the way.
في الطريق
Good.
جيد
You can take me with you,
يمكنك أن تأخذيني معك
so I can look after His Lordship
حتى أتمكن من الاعتناء بسيادته
and accompany you, Your Ladyship.
لمرافقتك يا سيدتك
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
نعم، نعم
I will go pack my belongings.
سأذهب لأحزم ممتلكات الخاصة بي
Good night.
طابت ليلتك
Why are you standing still?
لماذا تقف ساكنًا؟
Go pack your things.
أحزمي أغراضك
Do you not know
ألا تعرفين
how you got out of jail?
كيف خرجت من السجن؟
who spread
من نشر
your reputation for you?
سمعتك تجاهك؟
I invested so much effort!
استثمرت الكثير من الجهد!
Quickly.
هيا
What?
ماذا؟
I don't have any money now.
لا أملك أي نقود الآن
Take it.
خذه
I hope it's worth my while.
آمل أن يستحق كل هذا الوقت
So much.
جدا
It's my payment to you
إنه مدفوعات لك
for saving my reputation.
لإنقاذ سمعتي
Too much?
كثيرا؟
Give it back to me then.
أعده لي إذن
Well, it is worth my while.
حسنا، إنه يستحق فترة من الوقت
You will not have it back.
لن تستعيديها
Thanks.
شكرًا
(She's like)
(إنها تشبه)
(a whole different person.)
(شخص مختلف تماما)
(Ning's Mansion)
(حفل نينغ)
Your Ladyship, how thoughtful of you.
سيادتك، كم هو لطف منك
You've even prepared
لقد قمت حتى بإعداد
motion sickness relief unguent for Miss Wen.
إعانة المرض بالحركة للآنسة ون
I can't use that all up,
لا أستطيع استخدام كل هذا
so why not share it?
ولماذا لا تشارك فيها؟
And the other bottle
وزجاجة أخرى
is for His Lordship, right?
هي من أجل سيادته، صحيح؟
Shut up.
اخرس
Miss Wen,
الآنسة وين
I was going to see you.
كنت سأراك
What a coincidence, Sangyu.
يا لها من مصادفة يا سانغيو
I thought
أنا اعتقدت
the journey to Haifang
الرحلة إلى هايفانغ
would be bumpy,
سيكون متعبا
so…
لذلك
Here it is.
ها هو ذا
Motion sickness relief unguent.
تدابير الإغاثة في المرض لا تخمين
You may find it useful.
قد تجدها مفيدة
How thoughtful of you, Sangyu.
كم هو لطف منك يا سانغ يو
But
لكن
isn't it coincidental?
أليس من قبيل المصادفة؟
For I, too, have prepared
بالنسبة لي أيضًا، لقد أعدت
a small gift for you.
هدية صغيرة لك
What is it?
ما هي؟
It is the cowpeas
إنه اللوبيا
that are freshly picked in the countryside.
يتم اختيارها حديثًا في الريف
They are really fresh.
إنه طازج حقًا
It is my favorite food
إنه الطعام المفضل لي
made by my mother.
الذي صنعته أمي
So I cooked the dish
لذلك طهوت الطبق
the way my mother did,
كما فعلت أمي
and I want you to try it.
أريدك أن تجربها
I hope you like it.
آمل أن يعجبك
Sure.
بالطبع
I will give it a try.
سأجرّب
I'll take it.
سأعتبر ذلك
Thank you, Miss Wen.
شكرًا لك يا آنسة وين
Have it when it's hot.
خذها عندما تكون ساخنة
I will deliver more
سأقدم المزيد
to other rooms and His Lordship.
إلى الغرف الأخرى وإلى سيادته
OK.
حسنا
Come on, try it.
هيا، جربه
Have a go.
اذهب
Ning Yuxuan.
نينغ يويشوان
You've packed up your stuff?
لقد حزمت أغراضك؟
I don't have anything to pack up really.
ليس لديّ ما أحزمه حقًا
This is for you.
هذه لك
What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Motion sickness relief unguent.
اعفاء المرض من المرض بلا خداع
I gave one
أعطيت واحدا
to Miss Wen,
إلى الآنسة ون
and here's the only one left. You can have it.
وهنا هو الوحيد المتبقي يمكنك الحصول عليه
Thanks.
شكرًا
It's the first time
إنها أول مرة
I see a motion sickness relief unguent.
أرى مشكلة إغاثة مرضية غريبة
Weird stuff.
أشياء غريبة
Miss Wen put it here, didn't she?
وضعتها الآنسة وين هنا أليس كذلك
She just dropped it.
وقعت منها للتو
I haven't got around to it.
لم أعرفه
I'll be off.
سأذهب
Having a stomachache?
بألم في المعدة؟
Yeah.
نعم
But you should thank me,
ولكن يجب أن تشكريني
because if it wasn't me,
لأنه لم أكن أنا
you'd be the one
لكنك الشخص
who's having a stomachache.
الذي يعاني من ألم في المعدة
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
I ran into Miss Wen
صادفت الآنسة وين
earlier,
في وقت سابق
and she cooked some cowpeas.
وطهت بعض اللوبيا
She said it was the first time she tried to cook a dish like that,
قالت إنها المرة الأولى حاولت طبخ مثل ذلك
so she was inexperienced.
لذا كانت تفتقر إلى الخبرة
I tried some,
لقد جربت بعض
and it seems it wasn't cooked through.
ويبدو أنها لم تكن مطهية خلال اليوم
I think yours should be okay.
أعتقد أن طبقك يجب أن تكون بخير
Just give it a try.
جربها فحسب
Not cooked through?
ألا تطهو؟
How much did you eat?
كم أكلت؟
Not much.
لا بأس
It's really nice of her.
هذه لطيفة حقًا منها
Just try some.
تذوق القليل
Go back to your room and lie down.
عد إلى غرفتك واستلق
I'll get a doctor.
سأحضر طبيبًا
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
Just relax.
إهدأي
See you around.
أراكِ في الجوار
Have some.
استمتع
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
we will set off early in the morning tomorrow.
سنبدأ مبكرا في صباح الغد
Why aren't you in bed?
لماذا لست في السرير؟
Sit.
اجلس
I was about to go to bed.
كنت على وشك النوم
But I came immediately
لكنني جئت على الفور
as soon as
بمجرد أن
you summoned me.
استدعتني
Have some tea, Your Lordship.
تناول بعض الشاي يا سيادتك
It looks like
يبدو وكأنه
you are all set.
الأطعمة جاهزة
I have prepared
لقد قمت بإعداد
some snacks
بعض الوجبات الخفيفة
and the drugs that might be useful
والعقاقير التي قد تكون مفيدة
for the journey.
لهذه الرحلة
I have also made
لقد قمت أيضا
a light gown for you.
ثوب خفيف لك
We will set off tomorrow,
سننطلق غدا
so you have to be careful
لذلك يجب أن تتوخي الحذر
with what you eat tonight.
بما تأكلونه الليلة
Especially undercooked cowpeas.
خاصة الطاهي الداخلي الطهو
Thank you for your kind reminder.
شكرا لك على تذكيرك الكريم
I had a light dinner.
لدي عشاء خفيف
Undercooked cowpeas are poisonous.
اللوبيا غير المطهية سامة
You're aware of that, aren't you?
أنت تدرك ذلك، أليس كذلك؟
I have never heard of it.
لم أسمع أبدا عن ذلك
I personally
أنا شخصيا
gave the cowpeas that I cooked
أعطوا اللوبيا التي طهيتها
to Her Ladyship.
إلى سيدتها
Did…
هل...
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
I really didn't know
أنا حقا لا أعرف
that undercooked cowpeas were poisonous.
أن اللوبيا الموضوعة تحت الطهي كانت سامة
Her Ladyship is so nice to me.
سيدتها لطيفة جدا معي
And she proposed to take me to Haifang.
واقترحت اصطحابي إلى هيفانغ
How can I have the heart
كيف يمكنني الحصول على القلب
to harm her?
لأؤذيها؟
Sit down.
اجلس
You don't have to explain.
لا داعي لأن تشرح ذلك
You know exactly
أنت تعرف بالضبط
whether you did it on purpose or not.
سواء فعلت ذلك عن قصد أم لا
What do you mean, Your Lordship?
ماذا تعنين يا سيادتك؟
I didn't do that on purpose.
لم أفعل ذلك عن قصد
Wen Wan.
ون وان
I know that you held a grudge
أعلم أنك كنت تحمل ضغينة
against something happened before
ضد شيء حدث قبل ذلك
you were married or even earlier.
كنت متزوجة أو حتى قبل ذلك
But this is not
لكن هذا ليس
how you get even,
كيف تتساوى
do you understand?
هل تفهم؟
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
you saved my life.
لقد أنقذت حياتي
Without you,
بدونك
I don't even have the courage
ليست لدي الشجاعة حتى
to stay alive.
للبقاء على قيد الحياة
You're everything to me,
أنت كل شيء بالنسبة لي
Your Lordship.
سيادتك
Don't give me this nonsense.
لا تخبرني بهذا هراء
Stop your affectation.
كفي عن مشاعرك
You will
سوف
stay in the capital.
ابقي في العاصمة
Your Lordship…
سيادتك...
Think carefully
فكر بعناية
about what a life you will live.
عن الحياة التي ستعيشها
Nie Sangyu is no longer the person
لا تعد نيون سانغيوي الشخص
who she used to be.
الذي كانت تنتمي إليه
Ever since she woke from the coma after falling off the cliff,
منذ أن استيقظت من القصة المُصورة بعد أن سقطت من الهاوية
she has never done
لم تفعل أبدا
anything to harm you.
أي شيء لإيذائك
And what about you?
وماذا عنك؟
You should put a stop to it, no?
يجب أن توقف ذلك، لا؟
Your Lordship, it is all but a misunderstanding.
سيادتك، كل شيء ولكن سوء فهم
I didn't do it on purpose.
لم أفعل ذلك عن قصد
Your Lordship, please trust me.
سيادتك، يرجى الوثوق بي
I will set off tomorrow.
سأنطلق غدا
I need to go to bed.
يجب أن أذهب للنوم
Go back to your room now.
عد إلى غرفتك الآن
I will be praying for you
سأصلي من أجلك
in the capital.
في العاصمة
May Lord bless you.
أتمنى أن يباركك اللورد
Good night, Your Lordship.
طابت ليلتك يا جلالتك
(Nie Sangyu is guardless)
(ني سانغ يو ليس لديه حارس)
(after she lost her memory.)
(بعد أن فقدت ذاكرتها)
(I think I'd better warn her.)
(أعتقد أنني أفضل أن أحذرها)
Easy, everybody.
نعم، الجميع
Put it here.
ضعيه هنا
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
نعم
Here, here.
هنا
Take it slow.
خذ الأمر ببطء
(Ning's Mansion)
(حفل نينغ)
Gui Bai,
جي باي
how is it going?
كيف تسير الأمور؟
Your Lordship, we are ready.
سيادتك، نحن مستعدون
Your Ladyship.
سيادتك
Is my wife's stuff
هي أشياء زوجتي
all ready?
جاهزة تماما؟
Muxu got two crates here,
وضع موتشو صندوقين هنا
and they are on the carriage.
وهما على متن العربة
As for the rest,
أما بالنسبة للبقية
Her Ladyship insisted that she will carry them herself.
أصرت سيدتها على أنها أن تحملهم بنفسها
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Yeah.
نعم
All the important stuff
كل الأشياء الهامة
will stay with me.
سوف تبقى معي
Suit yourself.
ناظر نفسك
Mr. Liu,
السيد ليو
please look after the Mansion
يرجى الاعتناء بالقصر
while I'm away.
بينما أنا بعيدة
Sure thing, Your Lordship.
بالتأكيد، سيادتك
Your Lordship, it's about time.
جلالتك، لقد حان الوقت
We should get going.
يجب أن نذهب
(Ning's Mansion)
(حفل نينغ)
Your Ladyship,
سيادتك
take care of yourself.
اعتني بنفسك طوال الطريق
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
If I have time,
إذا كان لدي وقت
I will write a letter to you.
سأكتب رسالة إليكم
My dear, let's go.
عزيزي، دعنا نذهب
I need to go.
أحتاج إلى الذهاب
Wait.
انتظر
Your Lordship, give me a minute.
سيادتك، أمهلني دقيقة
It is hot and humid in Haifang,
إنه حار ورطب في هيفانغ
so I have prepared
لذلك قمت بإعداد
this straw mat for you, Your Lordship.
هذه القش لك يا سيادتك
I hope you take good care of yourself
آمل أن تعتني بنفسك جيدا
in Haifang.
في هيفانغ
I will keep a vegetarian diet
سأحتفظ بحمية نباتية
in the capital
في العاصمة
and pray for you.
واصلي من أجلك
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
I made a mistake.
ارتكبت خطأ
Please forgive me.
أرجوك سامحني
You should apologize
يجب أن تعتذر
to the First Lady.
إلى السيدة الأولى
Your Ladyship,
سيادتك
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف
I didn't know what I was thinking.
لم أكن أعرف ما أفكر فيه
Please forgive me
أرجوك سامحني
and take the straw mat.
وتناول الماصة
I forgive you.
أغفر لك
But please keep the straw mat.
ولكن أرجوك احتفظي بالماصة
Thank you for your forgiveness.
شكرًا لك على المغفرة لك
Farewell, Your Ladyship.
وداعا يا سيدتك
Safe travels.
السفر الآمن
(Ship Sea-returning)
(السفينة البحرية العائدة)
(Sang Shen)
(سانغ شين)
(Ji Ming)
(جي مينغ)
Sir!
سيدي!
- Sir. - Sang Shen.
- سيدي - سانغ شين
You are home, sir.
أنت إلى المنزل يا سيدي
I miss you so much.
أشتاق إليك كثيرًا
What took you so long?
ما الذي أخّرك؟
Alright, alright.
حسنًا لا بأس
Look how thin I am.
انظري إلى مدى رقيقة
I couldn't eat or sleep well without you.
لم أستطع أن آكل أو النوم جيدًا من دونك
Sir, have you eaten well?
سيدي، هل أكلت جيدًا؟
Sang Shen, where's Man'er?
سانغ شين، أين هو مان؟
Did you have fun?
هل استمتعت؟
Sang Shen!
سانغ شن!
For three months I was on the sea,
لمدة ثلاثة أشهر كنت في البحر
my daughter said she was in Haifang,
قالت ابنتي إنها في هيفانغ
but here you tell me
ولكن هنا قلت لي
that she left Haifang
أنها غادرت هيفانغ
two months ago.
قبل شهرين
Where did she go?
إلى أين ذهبت؟
Sir,
سيدي
she has gone to the capital…
ذهبت إلى العاصمة...
To… To…
إلى... وإلى...
Speak!
تكلم!
Sir,
سيدي
she has gone to the capital to see her love.
لقد ذهبت إلى العاصمة لرؤية حبها
Her love?
حبها؟
Ridiculous.
سخيفة
No.
لا
I will set off immediately
سأنطلق على الفور
to the capital.
إلى العاصمة
Yes, sir.
نعم سيدي
Who prepared these?
من حضّر هذه؟
How sweet!
كم هو حلو!
It's…
السيد ليو
I knew it was him.
كنت أعرف أنه هو
You must give him a raise.
يجب أن ترفعي له
OK.
حسنا
I got it.
فهمت
What are you reading?
ماذا تقرئين؟
Some information
بعض المعلومات
about Haifang.
عن هايفانغ
Is there anything interesting?
هل هناك أي شيء مثير للاهتمام؟
Share with me.
مشاركة معي
Haifang was originally a small fishing village
كان هايفانغ في الأصل قرية صغيرة لصيد الأسماك
that was sparsely populated.
كانت قليلة السكان
Pirates used to sell
تم استخدام القراصنة للبيع
their lootings
لبيعه
in Haifang.
في هيفانغ
With more and more merchants coming to the place,
مع المزيد من التجار بالمجيء إلى المكان
they chipped in
ثم شرعوا في
to build a private port.
لبناء ميناء خاص
Over the years, it's become
على مر السنين، أصبح
the place for oversea merchants
مكان التجار في عرض البحر
to trade merchandises.
لتجارة التجار
A market built by pirates?
سوق بناها القراصنة؟
The government did nothing?
الحكومة لا شيء؟
They couldn't do anything about it.
لا يمكنهم فعل شيء حيال ذلك
Three county magistrates
ثلاثة قضاة في المقاطعات
died mysteriously.
ماتوا في ظروف غامضة
The land of tigers and wolves.
أرض النمور والذئاب
It may refer to this place.
قد يشير إلى هذا المكان
Three county magistrates died mysteriously?
ثلاثة قضاة إقليميين مات في ظروف غامضة؟
So a local official may die tragically?
لذلك قد يموت مسؤول محلي بشكل مأساوي؟
So do you regret
لذلك هل أنت نادم
coming along with me?
أن تأتي معي؟
No way.
لا يمكن
I did my research, too,
قمت ببحوث أيضًا
before I came.
قبل أن آتي
Can you hear me out?
هل تسمعني؟
Tell me about it, then.
قل لي عن ذلك إذن
The most famous food in Haifang
أشهر الطعام في هيفانغ
is Li's Roast Chicken,
هو مطعم لي المحمص
Uncle Yao's Beef,
حبة العم ياو
Mrs. Song's Stew and Rice.
يخنة السيدة سونغ ورايس
Cai's Quail Soup is good, too.
رائحة الخمر تساي جيدة أيضًا
And Sticky Rice Ball with Meat Stuffing.
وخنزير الأرز اللزج مع تجميل الخمر
So this is the research you did?
هل هذا هو البحث الذي قمت به؟
Not just Haifang,
ليس فقط هيفانغ
I have studied all the good eating
لقد درست كل الطعام الصالح
along the way.
على طول الطريق
Stay with me, and you'll be well fed.
ابقي معي، وسوف تتغذى جيدا
Gui Bai,
جي باي
will we arrive in Jishui City soon?
هل سنصل إلى مدينة جيشوي قريبا؟
Yes.
نعم
I tell you what,
أقول لك ماذا
the rice there is wonderful.
الأرز هناك رائع
And Caozhou's beef…
واللحم البقري لـ كاوزهو
After working with him for years,
بعد العمل معه لسنوات
I'm very clear what he's like
أنا واضح جدا كيف هو
as an opponent.
كمعارضة
He must have found something
يجب أن يكون قد وجد شيئا ما
or His Majesty wouldn't send him to Haifang.
وإلا لن يكون جلالة الإمبراطور أرسله إلى هيفانغ
Ning Yuxuan only has a few guards with him.
نينغ يويشوان فقط لديه بعض الحراس معه
He's vulnerable at the moment.
إنه ضعيف في الوقت الحالي
Take him down on his journey.
خذوه في رحلته
Yes.
نعم
Ning Yuxuan.
نينغ يوتشيوان
Can we take a break?
هل يمكننا أن نأخذ استراحة؟
What's the rush?
ما الاستعجال؟
It's a long way to Haifang.
انها طريق طويل إلى هيفانغ
There's no time to waste.
لا وقت للتضييع
You're not sleeping.
أنت لست نائمًا
Y-You startled me.
أفزعتني
(Linhai Post House)
(بيت ليهاي)
Your Lordship, we have arrived at a post house.
سيادتك، لقد وصلنا عند بيت البريد
We have?
حقًا؟
Gui Bai.
جي باي
Would you please talk to the owner
هل تفضل التحدث إلى المالك
to check us in?
للتحقق منا من ذلك؟
Why me?
لماذا أنا؟
Gui Bai can do it.
قوي باي
I will see to it.
سوف أراه
No, you will not.
لا، لن تفعل ذلك
Only you can get it done, my wife.
فقط يمكنك القيام بذلك يا زوجتي
Again, why me?
مجددًا، لماذا أنا؟
You have the title with you,
لديك اللقب معك
so they will offer you better rooms.
لذلك سوف يقدمون لك غرف أفضل
This is the reason
هذا هي السبب
why you brought me with you, huh?
لماذا أحضرتني معك يا هوه؟
You said it.
أنت قلت ذلك
Your rank is higher than mine.
رتبتك أعلى من رتبتي
The higher the rank,
كلما زادت الرتبة
the better the room.
كلما زادت الغرفة
Why wouldn't I take advantage of it?
لماذا لا يمكنني الاستفادة منها؟
You think I will fall for it?
هل تعتقد أنني سأُغرم بذلك؟
I don't believe you, Ning Yuxuan,
لا أصدقك، نينغ يويشوان
would be so petty.
سيكون تافهًا جدا
Tell me, what other reasons?
قل لي، ما هي الأسباب الأخرى؟
Well, there is
هناك سبب آخر
another reason.
سبب آخر
I knew it.
أنا عرفت ذلك
I bet
أراهن أنك
you feel honored
تشعرين بالشرف
to have me, an imperial mandate lady, with you, right?
أن يكون لديّ سيدة إمبراطورية مفوضة معك، أليس كذلك؟
I brought you with me
أحضرتك معي
because I wanted to make sure you wouldn't tear down my house.
لأنني أردت التيقن من أنكم لن تقضي على منزلي
You…
أنت...
I…
أنا...
Alright, give me back my bead.
حسنًا، أعد لي حبيبتي
Why?
لماذا؟
You begged me to bring you with me.
توسلت إليّ لإحضارك معي
Fine.
حسنا
I will get you
سأحضر لك
a premium room, then.
إذن
Muxu.
موشو
Thank you, my dear.
شكرا لك يا عزيزي
Check us in.
تحققي منا
(By God's will, I hereby appoint the wife of Marquis Moyu, Lady Nie Sangyu,)
(بإرادة الله، أعين بموجب هذا زوجة ماركيز مويو، السيدة ني سانغيو
(as the Second-rank Lady with Imperial Mandate.)
(كسيدة المرتبة الثانية) بالانتداب الإمبراطوري)
Your Ladyship.
سيادتك
Lean over.
اتكئ
Give me a woodshed.
أعطني محفظة
I don't think that's appropriate.
لا أظن أن هذا ملائم
That's fine.
لا بأس
OK.
حسنا
Put it away.
ضعه بعيدا
Your Ladyship, here's the key.
سيادتك، هنا المفتاح
Thanks.
شكرا
All done.
انتهيت
Which room will I live in?
أي غرفة سأعيش فيها؟
(Woodshed)
"مستهلك"
You will sleep in a woodshed, and I will sleep in a premium room.
سوف تنامين في حذاء وسأنام في غرفة تبرّج
Why woodshed for me?
لماذا حظت بالخشب لي؟
The owner said
قال المالك
that my status
إن مكانتي
only works for myself.
فقط يعمل من أجلي
No special treatment for the family.
لا توجد معاملة خاصة للأسرة
Nothing I can do, right?
لا يمكنني فعل شيء، صحيح؟
A premium room
غرفة علاوة
is a standard offer for a rank 2 titled lady,
هو عرض موحد للمرتبة الثانية بعنوان سيدة
and a woodshed is for a rank-7 county magistrate.
وصرف الحطب هو لـ قاضي مقاطعة من الرتبة السابعة
You figure it out.
ستجدين الأمر
Don't you have anything to say?
ألا لديك ما تقوله؟
Nothing.
لا شيء
It surprises me that Ning Yuxuan
يفاجئني أن نينغ يويشوان
didn't fight me over the premium room.
لم تشارك معي بشأن غرفة الأقساط
I haven't had a chat with them for a long time.
لم أتناول محادثة معهم لفترة طويلة
Your Lordship,
سيادتك
I just led my men on a patrol
كنت أقود رجالي فقط في دورية
around the post house,
حول منزل الوظيفة
and we found nothing.
ولم نجد شيئًا
Search again.
ابحث مرة أخرى
I don't think Ling Jianxing
لا أعتقد أن لينغ جيانشينغ
would miss out on the opportunity.
سوف يفوت الفرصة
It cannot be
لا يمكن أن يكون
a quiet journey.
رحلة هادئة
Yes, Your Lordship.
نعم، سيادتك
I haven't seen so many stars in such a long time.
لم أر كل هذا النجوم في مثل هذا الوقت الطويل
I tell you what,
أنا أخبرك بما هو
I met some weird people
قابلت بعض الناس الغريب
recently,
في الآونة الأخيرة
some weird things,
وبعض الأشياء الغريبة
and a very dislikeable person.
وشخص مشابه جدا
(Consul Ning.)
(القنصل نينغ)
You are lucky
أنت محظوظ
to have a good wife.
أن يكون لديك زوجة صالحة
Now, the entire capital city
الآن، العاصمة بأكملها
knows that the Ning family
تعرف أن عائلة نينغ
has been loyal for generations,
كانت وفية لأجيال
and that Marquis Moyu was framed.
وأنه تم تأطير ماركيز مويو
As we speak,
بينما نتحدث
those petitioners who support you
أولئك الملتمسون الذين يؤيدكم
are swarming
يحرسون
outside the gate of my palace.
خارج بوابة قصري
I apologize, Your Majesty.
أعتذر يا صاحب الجلالة
I have a playful wife.
لدي زوجة صالحة
I assure you
أؤكد لك
that she shall be disciplined.
أنها ستكون منضبطة
Again,
مرة أخرى
thanks to your wife,
بفضل زوجتك
my problem
مشكلتي
has been solved.
تم حلها
She gave me a reason
أعطتني سببا
to release you.
للإفراج عنك
Arise.
تبرز
Come forth.
تعال
I'm aware
أنا أدرك
that you were framed.
أنك كنت مؤطر
But do you know
ولكن هل تعرف
who did it?
من فعل ذلك؟
I have done an investigation.
لقد قمت بتحقيق
And everything
وكل شيء
leads to Haifang.
يؤدي إلى هيفانغ
I knew I could trust you.
كنت أعرف أنني أستطيع الوثوق بك
Haifang is a place
هايفانغ هو مكان
full of oversea merchants.
مليء بالتجار في عرض البحر
It cannot be avoided
لا يمكن تفاديه
on the way to the central plains.
في الطريق إلى السهول المركزية
In the past,
في الماضي
my late father's
مشروع نظام المقاطعات
county system project failed in Haifang.
فشل مشروع نظام المقاطعات في هيفانغ
The local merchants
التجار المحليون
collided with the bandits,
اصطدام مع قطاع الطرق
and almost took
وكادت أن تأخذ
over the administrative authority
السلطة الإدارية
of Haifang.
من هيفانغ
The officials that I sent there
المسؤولون الذين أرسلتهم إلى هناك
either joined them
إما انضموا إليهم
or died in mysterious ways.
أو ماتت بطرق غامضة
Haifang is in Lord Tan's jurisdiction.
هايفانغ في ولاية اللورد تان
I volunteer to
أنا متطوع
go to Haifang.
الذهاب إلى هيفانغ
I knew you are the right person.
كنت أعرف أنك الشخص الصحيح
You will help me
سوف تساعدني
take over the administrative authority.
تولي السلطة الإدارية
The place
المكان
must be under my rule.
يجب أن يكون تحت حكمي
It will be a pioneer area
سيكون قطاعا رائدا
for the tax reform.
للإصلاحات الضريبية
You will govern the place,
سوف تحكم المكان
and I'm sure
وأنا على يقين
Haifang has
هايفانغ لديه
great potential.
قدرة كبيرة
Then, I'll have a reason
إذن، سيكون لدي سبب
to transfer you back to the capital.
لنقلها مرة أخرى إلى العاصمة
Understood, Your Majesty.
مفهوم يا صاحب الجلالة
(The journey to Haifang shall be precarious.)
(ستكون الرحلة إلى هايفانغ خطيرة)
(Dad, please look over me)
(أبي، أرجوك انظر إليّ)
(and help me find the remnants of the Tea Gang.)
(لمساعدتي في العثور على البقايا) من تاي غانغ)
(I will avenge you)
(سأنتقم منك)
(and bring peace to the country)
(لإحلال السلام في البلد)
(so you can rest in peace.)
(حتى تتمكن من الراحة في سلام)
But soon, I will
ولكن قريبا، سأكون
be in a new place.
سأكون في مكان جديد
I hope…
آمل...
I hope things can be different
آمل أن تكون الأمور مختلفة
at this new place,
في هذا المكان الجديد
so I can forget about
لذلك يمكنني أن أنسى
all the annoying stuff.
عن كل الأشياء المزعجة
If…
لو
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
I…
أنا...
I'm taking a walk.
سأغادر
What are you doing here?
ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Taking a walk?
المشي؟
If you want your room changed,
إذا كنت تريد تغيير غرفتك
you can forget about it.
يمكنك نسيان الأمر
Tomorrow
غدا
will be a bright day.
سيكون يومًا مشرقًا
Look at all those shining stars.
انظروا إلى كل هذه النجوم المظلمة
You know these?
هل تعرفين هذه؟
You don't believe me?
هل تصدقني؟
You'll see tomorrow
سترى غدًا
if I'm right or not.
إذا كنت على حق أم لا
Ning Yuxuan,
نينغ يوتشوان
look.
انظر
Look at that star.
انظروا إلى ذلك النجم
The brightest one.
أكثر إشراقًا
Do you know what it's called?
هل تعرف اسمها؟
What?
ماذا؟
You don't know, huh?
ألا تعرفين يا هو؟
It is Triads.
إنها ثلاثية
It appears at that point
يظهر في تلك المرحلة
every single day.
كل يوم
I saw it back in the Mansion,
رأيتها في قصر الأمم
but it wasn't this bright.
لكنها لم تكن مشرقة
Also,
وأيضًا
opposite to it
المقابل له
is a star
هو نجم
called Heart.
يسمى القلب
Those two stars
هذين النجوم
will never meet.
لن يجتمعا أبدا
When one comes out, the other goes away.
عندما يخرج أحدهما والآخر يزول
Whenever
كلما
the two of them appear,
لا يظهر الاثنان
you can judge the next day's weather
يمكنك الحكم على طقس اليوم التالي
and the current hour
و الحالية
through their positions
من خلال مواقعهم
and the hour they appear.
وساعة الظهور
Pretty cool, huh?
رائع جدًا يا هوه؟
When did you
متى تعلمت الخيول
learn horoscope?
تعلم المطرقة؟
It's very simple.
إنه بسيط جدا
I don't know
لا أعرف
when I learned it.
عندما تعلمته
It just popped
لقد انهار للتو
out of my mind suddenly.
فقدت عقلي فجأة
Also,
وأيضا
their positions
مواقعهم
and the hours,
وساعات العمل
these are simple knowledge.
هذه مجرد معرفة
It's not so difficult.
ليست صعبة جدا
So did something else
وكذلك فعلت شيئًا آخر
pop out
مبيد آفات شديد الخطورة
of your mind?
من عقلك؟
Something else?
شيء آخر؟
For example,
على سبيل المثال
memories from the past.
ذكريات من الماضي
No.
لا
Everything that they told me
كل ما قالوا لي
that I did before,
أنني فعلت من قبل
I don't remember anything.
أنا لا أتذكّر أي شيء
I don't mind not having any friends.
لا أمانع في عدم وجود أصدقاء
I've got the stars.
لديّ النجوم
The stars are my friends.
النجوم هي أصدقائي
Here's another secret of mine.
هنا سر آخر عني
I used to sneak out
كنت أتسلل
to talk to the stars
للحديث مع النجوم
all the time.
طوال الوقت
Talk to the stars?
مع النجوم؟
Yeah.
نعم
I need your shoulder.
أحتاج إلى كتفك
What?
ماذا؟
You know what?
هل تعرف
Someone told me
قال لي أحدهم
that every dead one on Earth
أن كل شخص ميت على الأرض
would turn into a star in the sky,
سوف يتحول إلى نجم في السماء
and they would
و كانوا
watch over us
راقبنا
from the sky.
من السماء
Will they…
هل...
♪Another round of wax and wane♪
♪ جولة أخرى من الشمع والتراجع ♪
...really turn into stars?
تتحول إلى نجوم حقًا؟
Yeah.
نعم
What's more,
ما هو أكثر من ذلك
when you think of them,
عندما تفكر فيهما
they think of you.
إنهم يفكرون بك
Their love for us
حبهم لنا
never disappears.
لا يختفي أبدا
They just love
إنهم يحبون فقط
and protect us
ويحميوننا
at another place.
في مكان آخر
♪A glimpse to build a bond♪
♪ لمحة لبناء رابطة ♪
Anyone you love up there?
أي شخص تحبه هناك؟
Or anyone you miss?
أي شخص تشتاقين إليه؟
♪Wish to pick the stars with you♪
♪ أرغب في اختيار النجوم معك ♪
Thanks.
شكرا
What?
ماذا؟
Nothing.
لا شيء
♪In the vicissitudinous world Love never changes♪
♪ في العالم المتحضر الحب لا يتغير أبدًا ♪
♪Summer stars, autumn night♪
♪ نجوم الصيف، ليلة الخريف ♪
♪Who is wandering under the moon in my heart♪
♪ من يتكاسل القمر في قلبي ♪
♪The deepest story with the shallowest goodbye♪
♪ أعمق قصة الوداع الأكثر ضحالة ♪
♪After passing by, I can only meet you in my dream♪
♪ بعد المرور من هنا لا يمكنني إلا أن ألتقي بك في حلمي ♪
♪The wind can't breeze the long street of time♪
♪ لا يمكن للرياح أن تنمو طريق الوقت الطويل ♪
♪The burning yearning will never cool♪
♪ الشوق المحترق لن يكون رائعا أبدا ♪
♪Two hearts meet again foreshadowing love♪
♪ قلبتان يلتقيان مرة أخرى وينذر بالحب ♪
♪How can I describe it when we look into each other's eyes♪
♪ كيف يمكنني وصفها عندما ننظر في عيون بعضنا البعض ♪
♪Take a life time to write the story♪
♪ خذوا وقت حياة لكتابة القصة ♪
♪Together with you♪
♪ معك ♪
♪Company you♪
♪ الارتباط معك ♪
♪Just for your glance and smile♪
♪ فقط من أجل نظرك وابتسامك ♪
♪The first promise means the forever love♪
♪ الوعد الأول يعني الحب إلى الأبد ♪
♪Fireworks all over the sky light up your night♪
♪ الألعاب النارية في جميع أنحاء السماء ضيء ليلتك ♪
♪Take a life time♪
♪ أخذ وقت الحياة ♪
♪To write the story with you gradually♪
♪ لكتابة القصة معك تدريجيا ♪
♪Just like this♪
♪ هكذا ♪
♪Our love goes on and on♪
♪ حبنا يستمر في النهاية ♪
♪The day we first met, the year when we get old♪
♪ اليوم الذي التقينا فيه لأول مرة السنة عندما نتقدم في السن ♪
♪My heart and my love will never vanish♪
♪ قلبي وحبي لن يختفي أبدًا ♪